# **Zulfiquer Mohammad Mizanur Rhaman (Bipool)**

Full Stack Developer at Apple Inc

### Summary

Having 11+ years professional experience in software development, mostly worked on web based application but capable of taking over any technology.

Started my professional career with LAMP development but last 4+ years working with J2EE based application. Have significant experience to work on frontend development in JavaScript, HTML5, AngularJS and jQuery. I like to work on spring framework.

Currently, holds a bachelor degree in Computer Science and Engineering and PHP Zend Certification.

#### Specialties On:

- \* Software Development (Java, Spring, EJB, JPA/Hibernate, Php, javaScript, AngularJs)
- \* Software Architecture.
- \* Database Design
- \* Performance and Scalability
- \* SOA
- \* Payment processing system

## Experience

#### **Full Stack Developer at Apple**

March 2017 - Present

#### **Software Engineer at Granbury Solutions**

August 2012 - February 2017 (4 years 6 months)

Developing a new point of sale for handheld device from scratch. Introduced SOA architecture for company which was a big change for company. Developing a new online ordering system. Beside these update and trouble shooting for existing point of sale.

- Developing J2EE web services (SOAP and REST) using EJB 3.0, JBOSS, Hibernate, JMS, RabbitMQ
- Developing frontend side by using AngularJS, JQuery, gulp,
- Working on mobile application for online order.
- Integrated Cayan EMV solution.
- Integrated EFT Pos Payment Processor

- Integrated Google map v3 with driving direction and street view
- Integrate Digital persona Finger print reader
- Using Jira for project/task management
- Using git for version controlling. Have experience to use SVN.
- Using maven for project deployment.
- Test Driven Development using jUnit, Mockito
- Database management

#### VP (Vice President) of Product Development at TigerIT Bangladesh Limited

July 2011 - July 2012 (1 year)

Responsibilities:

- \* Managing the project
- \* Communicate with client for project specification
- \* Design and Develop new project specification
- \* Hiring and guiding junior developers

#### AVP (Assistant Vice President) of Product Development at TigerIT Bangladesh Limited

February 2010 - June 2011 (1 year 4 months)

- \* Design and Develop new project specification
- \* Hiring and guiding/training junior developers
- \* Communicate with client for project specification

#### Senior Software Engineer at TigerIT Bangladesh Limited

February 2008 - January 2010 (1 year 11 months)

- \* Design and Develop new project specification
- \* Trouble shooting
- \* Hiring and guiding new developers

#### **Software Engineer**

August 2004 - January 2008 (3 years 5 months)

- \* Design and Develop new project specification
- \* Bug Fixed
- \* DB management
- \* Guiding new developers

#### Education

#### **Asian University of Bangladesh**

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.), Computer Science & Engineering, 2000 - 2004

# Honors and Awards

Zend Certfied Engineer

# Zulfiquer Mohammad Mizanur Rhaman (Bipool)

Full Stack Developer at Apple Inc



Contact Zulfiquer Mohammad on LinkedIn